Jonathan Brunt • Software Engineer

GitHub: https://github.com/jonbrunt Portfolio: https://jmbrunt.com Email: jbrunt.mobile@gmail.com

Summary

A Full-Stack Development Professional with success providing effective solutions for demanding business, technology and customer requirements. Strengths include extensive knowledge of user interface and user experience, servers, networks, hosting environments, relational and nonrelational databases. A reputation for utilizing an extensive understanding of how to interact with APIs and external touch-points, Quality Assurance, and Security concerns throughout the entire development lifecycle, while fulfilling customer and business needs.

Technology Skills

JavaScript • Python • C • React • Redux • Node • Express • MongoDB • SQL • Git/Version Control • SASS • LESS • D3.js User Interface • User Experience • Servers • Networks • Hosting Environments

Professional Experience

Consultant, Houston, TX

8/2007-Present

<u>Lambda School</u>

Software Engineer, Section Supervisor

6/2018-Present 7/2018-Present

Manage six Project Managers, mentor and supervise 40+ students while they learnt and utilized JavaScript, HTML, CSS,

LESS, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, SQL, Python, Django, and C skillsets.
Drive the implementation of a Master Based Progression to support students' goals to reach SP80 status and

- Drive the implementation of a Master Based Progression to support students' goals to reach SP80 status and progress to capstone project and graduation
- Plan and deliver one-on-one consultations with students and staff improving the student passing rate from 60% to 98% reaching passing status in the didactic portion

Software Engineer, Project Manager

6/2018-7/2018

Managed, mentored, and graded students for skills including JavaScript, HTML, CSS, LESS, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, SQL, Python, Django, and C.

- Results enabled 100% of students to achieve a passing score of 80% on exams
- Received a 2.83/3.0 student satisfaction rating, significantly higher than the school-wide average
- Achieved 8.66/10.0 Net Promoter Score, used to gauge likeliness of student to recommend the program, significantly higher that the school-wide average
- Promoted to Section Supervisor of another cohort after only five weeks in the position

BPM Marketing

8/2018-Present

Software Engineer

Hired on a part time basis to maintain and scale a portfolio of full-stack websites and applications for 10+ clients by leading web and application development projects.

- Plan and build a production application from inception through completion
- Technologies used include JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SASS, PHP, multiple custom Content Management Systems, ASP.NET, Digital Ocean, and Amazon S3
- Scale the server of a movie premiere website in production to reach 15 million consumers via email to promote the online release date and simultaneously build-out the front end
- Optimize an ASP.NET server of a B2C music storefront site to support thousands of rentals
- Increase server capacity of a large waste management equipment site to handle \$100K+ daily orders
- Improve the front-end of various retail sites

Independent Consultant 8/2017-Present

Full Stack JavaScript Development, MongoDB, Express, React, Node Execute multiple full-stack development projects for independent clients.

Independent Consultant 8/2007-7/2017

Biostatistician, Epidemiologist Consultant

- Developed and applied skills needed to understand determinants of disease and improve health
- Utilized descriptive and analytic approaches to investigate the complex causes of major public health problems

Education

University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston, TX 2006-2007

Public Health / Epidemiology / Biostatistics

University of Houston, Houston, TX 1998-2002

Biochemistry/Chemistry